but I was a kid like when I was a kid I
was in mid 20s and I was at college I
was studying like psychology and
sociology and whatever and then I feel
come to the realization that if I
carried along that path you know like
I've basically become some left-wing
fucking middle-class hypocrite and I'm
not I didn't go on that path I walked
straight out of society and I found that
yeah I am a very small minority people
were our age it was still sort of saying
yeah we want to fuck Volusion you know
peaceful peaceful revolution I mean if
yeah I'm still thinking about the
left-wing you know because one of the
reasons why within this state of affairs
that were in yeah we're yo we have such
inequality and where everything has to
be so pc in a very less haven't properly
made their case they've gone into this
whole PC identity thing they've gone
into so like yeah they've basically so
you know you're a pretty pressing thing
that's not your you're pressing my
person they want everything nice within
capitalism so you know yo if you're
black or you're yellow or you're why
capitalism treats you the same if
whatever your gender capitalism treats
you the same and when we've got like
that we're all happy capitalism is a
success especially you know in York as
well we got this whole sort of like
left-wing so neat what we called
neoliberalism is really left-wing
thinking is its left-wing capitalism
yeah I don't know I don't know how
left-wing it is I I actually think it's
pretty I think it's actually pretty
conservative yeah likely yeah the mask
of liberalism would actually a
conservative yeah
yeah but then it's not as conservative
as say weakest we smug physic you know
and that conservative in the sense that
it preserves capital and power in the
places where it has always been it's
conservative in that sense yeah no I
mean it's not conservative input in
terms of preserving family values and
and and that kind of stuff no not quite
the reverse in fact that's right yeah
yes
community bonding and so on is
antithetical to exploit the exploitation
that the system requires robbers yeah
once you start nothing under on that
daily level of sort of like compromising
your values very soon you don't have
those values anymore yeah absolutely
what happens a lot of people you know
they caught young and so idealistic but
they've come to the materialistic world
they've got a knuckle down get the
mortgage gets insecure aid you know they
compromise your values every day and
slowly you know they become cynical
people and they become cynical because
of the choices they make and younger I
mean I was a teacher for about 10 15
years and you know you watch kids when
they arrive at secondary school at 11
and they're they're still little kids
you know what I mean they're still full
of fun and whatever by the time they're
1415 they've been ground down by the
expectations of GCSEs coming up and then
they're gonna have to do an application
and you know applications for lodgings
and applications for financing and blah
blah blah blah blah blah blah and you
know I watched an Alan Watts thing about
this he's brilliant Alan Watson and if
you ever listen to me yeah yeah yeah but
you know he talks about exactly this
that you're always working towards
something in the future and that thing
never ever ever comes you know me you go
through school working towards your old
levels and your a-levels and your
university degree and then your post
doctoral degree and then your you know
your junior role in a job and looking to
again seniority again and all the time
you're thinking I'm when I do this then
I'm there when I do this and I'm there
and you never ever get there
it's ya dangled in front of you the
whole time before you know you're in
your
and he's never never once stopped
actually enjoyed your life yeah yeah
yeah it's raised well I was canvassing
once on a local election the field guide
come out and he goes oh I'm not voting
anymore I said oh why is that lady goes
well since I've retired I've had time to
think and that sort of like put it so
like into my head most people don't
think because they're too busy working I
said well maybe you should have thought
about things a bit before you retired
who's got the time right you're up now
commute home you got all this old
politics of being at work and the social
relationships all distracting you and
yeah it's like yeah I mean I don't
actually think that thinking is the
problem it's the having a moment to stop
thinking that's that's what people yeah
yeah Bob Lee yeah yeah I was listening
to Eckhart Tolle Reese Eckhart Tolle
recently and he talks a lot about that
is that they are addicted to thinking
right and and yeah yeah we don't need to
stop thinking can you actually realize
things if you know yeah but most of the
time we're not thinking at all are we we
just solve like repeating the same thing
over with our heads you know and so this
is just sort of like it's just so great
and absorbs our awareness it takes all
that's it yeah yeah that's it and it
reinforces what we believe in I think
it's George Bernard Shaw he he once
quoted because I have become famous
because I think I think about once or
twice a month he was quite a wise
self-aware guy you know because both you
think what I'm thinking all the time I'm
not thinking that way
actually no you know what's going on in
your head it's just stuff you've heard
before and you know it's not it's not
really thinking well it's hard I mean
Jordan Peterson talks a lot about this
the thinking is hard you know I mean
very few people are capable of doing it
at an individual level because it
requires you to take
opposing positions and and really try
and
be strong in each position people who
actually pred to do that we've got our
own what we think we're not there to
really try and undermine what we already
think why you need more than one person
to think you know what I mean you've got
a head shouting yeah yeah let's talk
about the movement for a little while
she and I'm very critical but wait how
do you feel about how the movement
progressed in the last ten years
well destroy when you say the movement
what are you referring to a
resource-based economy I don't I think
it's progressed in the last ten years
very very disappointingly I mean I when
I came to it was so exciting to me know
me was about four years ago now
something like that when I first came
through it was it was it was super
exciting and I thought my god how is
this not you know how this is not being
widely discussed but the thing is Nick
for whatever reason busy other things
going on don't want to look at it scary
whatever people do not want to see how
broken no broken is not even the wrong
word how unfit for purpose our systems
of money and politics and power
distribution and wealth distribution and
so on are they just don't they just
don't want to see it you know what I
mean because they can't imagine anything
different we're so entrenched in it
we're so conditioned to it people can't
imagine anything different and I you
know I realize that I'm in a unique
position because I don't have kids I
don't have any dependents you know what
I mean I don't have financial worries
particularly you know I've retired now I
don't have financial worry I'm in a very
very very unique position so I'm free to
change my view of the world it doesn't
really can't just do that they can't do
that but I understand why it hasn't got
a foothold because it is it is
unbelievably radical it requires a
complete re-evaluation of the way you
see yourself
and the world and the relationship
between those two things you know what I
mean
and okay yeah I do understand what you
mean and I can sort of have some
sympathy and even empathy for that
position but I tend not to agree you
know I don't think that is the reason
why we're not getting hurt yeah I think
the reason why we're not getting hurt is
basically we don't want to share our
value add to movement we don't want to
share about it so maybe you know we're
too frightened fire because we're scared
of not succeeding which is a shit reason
Emilio shit why because I'm scared I
might fail is a shit reason for not
doing something so you know we have
probably hundreds of thousands of
supporters across the globe domi
probably more actually and we would
probably get a lot more if eminent
eminent people in our movement or people
who make themself emmeline they're
moving had the bottle to go outside and
get arrested for what they believe in
at the moment we're bit like the left
wings of neoliberals you know our
movements or like oh let's get into
non-violent communication let's not be
antagonistic and we go mouth at
soft-serve Road ugly know where we need
to be more militant we need leaders that
can inspire people to take action we
need leaders that can enthuse people and
tell them that it is their mine to live
in an intelligently and equitably
managed society and to somehow sort of
get that embodied inside them and inside
other people enough to take out onto the
streets enough to sort of like say well
I'm gonna make my stand here and if
we've all as a movement have got that
same goal that say no bring it into
public debate we want our goal in public
debate yeah there may be we are
movements got a chance we going forward
yeah but I think it's not gonna go
forward every unless we have that goal
of
into public debate so doing series of
steps then and have you got anyone in
mind for these these these leaders that
can inspire people to get out there
Colin Turner Peter Joseph yeah I mean if
they did something together as
individuals and got themselves arrested
together they were not only unified a
movement but they would inspire other
people to go out and do the same I mean
I thought yeah I will walk the walk as
well as talk the talk yeah but I think
it's just gonna yeah we just got to
change our attitude from this soft saw
of light and I don't want to upset
people approach to sort of like hey this
is my my you know my right and
everybody's right to live in a peaceful
planet you know to live in a
well-managed to planet to live in an
equitable planet and yeah we've got to
be standing up and saying because until
we stand up and say that it's not gonna
happen
Peter Joseph has been doing exactly that
for 10 years or more now I mean he gives
lectures he does interviews on TV yeah
yeah he writes books yeah yeah give him
his give him his due he has a lot he's
done a lot yeah yeah he hasn't gone out
on the streets and confronted confronted
the authorities in order to get arrested
kind of thing I agree I'm thankful day
exists you know but I think I think it's
just where do stuff first of all I'm
gonna leave him yeah loosely poto side
and just so like look at tzm and tzm and
not like that are they know their idea
of radical is to go out once a year with
a wall paper pacing table onto a high
street and give away leaflets and free
hugs yeah that's as bad as so like
medical as a go so somehow you you know
Peter Joseph hasn't been able to yeah
I don't know what the word is but he
hasn't been out to produce a movement
that can reflect the militancy that's
needed
yeah but I would say if you had an army
of people going out every weekend to
high streets with wallpaper tables and
giving out leaflets and offering free
hugs if you had dozens or hundreds of
people doing that every single weekend
that's different right now that's
different yeah that's different because
if you look at the yeah the psychology
of how minorities change the values of
the majority then consistency yes
correct
it's one of the major influences you've
got to be consistent yeah you've got to
keep doing it and yeah so so yeah it is
and that that would really help mean
there's these other things that we can
do do to you know to help raise
awareness as well but generally that's
where we're I believe here we've we
gotta go because you know we created the
money free pie and it allows people to
vote for you know direct transition to a
resource-based economy but it doesn't
create the value shift that's needed to
vote for that yeah yeah okay and so yo
Colin Turner he's sort of like into he's
been focusing attention on creating sort
of like a free swap Club yeah yeah yeah
but that doesn't take off because there
isn't enough people yo doing it because
there's not because that value change
start somewhere I mean yeah yeah well is
it but the thing is the fan you change
as far as I'm aware you know and looking
back in history happens when we go out
and as a minority and we start to
confronting the values of the majority
that's when the blacks when and how the
value shifts happening
that happens you know and that's kind of
what we got doing and and making
whatever alternative currencies or
alternative ways to swap and trade
they're not gonna do it they they do
allow the facilitation of of what we
want to see but they don't create that
value change that value change is going
to occur the fact that these things are
popping into existence is indicative of
the fact that those value changes are
starting to occur right otherwise why
these I think I think there's I think a
seed of something I think yeah
well naturally you know everything
changes including values okay and so now
we get on to sort of like a new world
right if the world is continually
evolving society's evolving and the way
I see the society evolving you know it's
gonna be we're gonna so basically
reinforce this three-tier society that
we've got now where we've got you know
the elites right at the top okay we're
there with ya and they just tell me to
talk about them then we got there that
the favored professionals and the lucky
ones living in their gated communities
you know and then at the bottom you know
we've got all the masses of called
people and those poor people they're
gonna be in the future they're gonna be
living off of sort of like what we call
the collective Commons okay they'll be
scraping around for scraps from the
collective Commons you bi yo Universal
bakes we can become that might even be
part paid in crypto currencies by the
time we get it rolled out and so it's
yeah is indicative of what we're saying
so like you know swabbing and free stuff
you know of goods and services but there
are very low-level goods goods and
services yeah and not what we they want
value there isn't the trust in that
system yet right for people is it there
isn't it trust and also there isn't the
capital to go into it there's not the
resources to go into that system no I
mean Colin's vision is one of us sort of
slowly accreting
snowball rolling down and
ever-increasing slope you know to me and
so it starts very very very slowly but
as it picks up speed that brings more
you know that encourages more people to
come into it and it's like a exponential
once once you've reached a certain point
it's like if you know like an
exponential runaway thing I think he's
got a point but this but the beginning
the beginning is as you say there isn't
the value shift in the minds of the
people in the society to drive them
towards the use of those kinds of
systems but then the increasing use of
those kinds of systems will start to
create those values you know I mean it's
a yeah if you do get an increasing
increasing use I mean what happened with
the let system you familiar with the let
the let's yeah that's cool okay uh
fillion local exchange trading systems
okay okay and these took off in the 80s
and I say they took off
they took off they went they went they
were noble they would so like every
local sub area all over the world well
all over the Western world anyway you
know we had them throughout Europe we
had begot systems in America all over
the UK nearly every area in the UK
hasn't or had them they still exist
somewhat is what happens is yeah when we
create and basically they were an
alternative currency you know
theoretically with let's
theoretically with this you could
basically resolve global poverty yeah
that's so like theoretic you could do
that yeah if you've got people using
them but yeah the people didn't use them
no they started off not people using
them but not enough people use them to
make them powerful enough and slowly
they em away and there's to exist in
lots of places let's local exchange
train systems but they've got no sort of
real power you know to make any
difference because not enough people use
them and the other worry that the value
change is not happen modified right in
this day and age what it would any of
this kind of thing that emerges soon
gets commodified look what happened to
Bitcoin right you know yeah yeah into a
tool of speculation explosive yeah boom
that's it's dead no one no one can
possibly trust that thing as a currency
anymore right yeah that's yeah that's
that's another there is no discussion
there but yeah yeah I mean so when
Bitcoin was coming on to it was saying
are the money free by still get into
Bitcoin yeah it's it's gonna take us
it's gonna be the transition to a money
free world you know and it's the same
thing with you Bri you know you've got
to get be our newbie I kiss you be eyes
gonna transition it's all these things
yeah they're not really we and and
that's one of the problems with the
movement is we're so distracted you know
by every little new thing that's on the
show oh that's gonna help us to towards
a resource-based economy that's gonna
help us to post monetary society the
only thing that's gonna help us towards
a post monetary society inflation by
having that shared goal going out and
demand in that goal that's what's gonna
help us get there yeah quite the idea of
armies of people going and setting up
tables and offering free hugs you know
like hundreds of people doing it in town
centres all over the country every
weekend know what I mean I I actually
really like the idea of that it is
confrontational but not in a you know
not in a no noise yeah I mean I know I
could do a bit better than that to be
honest with you but I've been only try
to organize a gig locally so a music
geek because I'm I'm in the middle of
helping south of community festival one
moment and something in stuff like doing
a benefit gig for so like a post
mandatory society so I'll get sort of
like fine fine of a few local bands that
would do it for me and then a venue and
then yeah it's small local bands they
bring their own sort people and they're
quite half into playing for nothing they
just want to play basically you know so
get all their supporters in and then if
they go out they get an introduction
into the concept yeah post mostly
Society and also an invitation to
another meeting
which would sort of like help their
education and understanding the
post-motor 'i saw a bit Beth but also be
a sort of table to talk about how to get
that message into mainstream if I can do
that it's successful I want to get like
half a dozen people and we're trying to
do that all over the country and so
we'll start having sort of like local
benefit gigs and try to sort of like
maybe get a new sort of support base
because it'll open our support base it
just doesn't it's not doing the trees
not doing what we want it to do with it
yeah that sounds good and it's a it's
the right kind of crowd as well right so
it's a it's a young hip yeah crowd so ya
know it's the right kind of people have
you ever seen mother site-geist
presentations in their path have you
ever seen one of the presentations
towards I went to this up in London they
used to hang about in this pub and do a
presentation every week and they're
quite entertaining in some ways um you
you know if personally if I go into the
street if I have a few people with me
what I would do it's basically do part
of a side glass presentation and I
wouldn't go out with the store I'd go
out with a couple of people just to back
me up and I just so go into the
marketplace start cap and go coming come
here when you get back to six people
round go right now everybody laughs
laughs get them laughing and the more
people come so I'm not gonna tell you
what I want to tell you it took more
people here get a good group people
around you you know and then do a
presentation sort of like on how money
is created give everybody force money
save you living on an island show them
out interest works and just do a nice
tzm presentation you be a bit more
proactive than just having a wallpaper
that table there that's how I came
anyway exclusive right you know not
everyone is standing up my presentation
so what you saying is my it's
it would be great if we could do that
I'm sort of playing around we can
recount sooner or later you get on the
local news and then you get on the
national news and you know what I mean
now what is it these people are actually
talking about I mean initially it's just
oh isn't it funny these people handing
out free hugs or whatever giving him
prompt to presentation you know isn't it
funny isn't it quirky but later they
start to talk about what you're talking
about it's been it's being consistent
again is it I mean you look at the you
look at the vegan movement and and you
go back to all yo something that
everybody can get behind you know people
hate the vegans especially ten years ago
they were more so hated than they are
now even you know people begin to accept
them now but yeah they were very small
minority they were very radical yo and
and because they've been consistent in
their votes yeah yeah they've got more
respect and their movement has grown
potentially you know it's not absolutely
a really crucial thing there the
consistency keeping on doing and keeping
on doing it yeah absolutely yeah and and
of course motivation becomes an issue I
mean I think one of the things
extinction rebellion have done really
well is that they've organized these
sort of regular chapter meetings where
you know everyone gets together and they
exchange ideas and they have little
training sessions about how to cope with
various situations and so on and it
gives people a sense of involvement and
ongoing you know ongoing participation
and here we lack that kind of
infrastructure yeah yeah and we yeah
there's we have some different
organizations within the movement that
have different goals okay and there's no
sort of there's no channeling you know
there's no unified movement over that we
didn't it within the different groups in
fact they squabble amongst themselves
you know you couldn't and they fell out
okay so you know I was I mean I come
from a bit more of a sort of like a
socialist anarchist or background but
not that radical but when I
first come across the RBE movement I was
already somebody who wanted to promote a
money free world yeah and I come across
the RB movement and my first impressions
were these aren't activists it's like a
fanbase you know it's like a bunch of
groupings and I was I was talking to
somebody this English last week right in
a conversation who he's a very
influential much more influential than I
am within our movement and I'll tell you
what he said right or they said sorry um
this is the cry it's a bit long so
really dad the vast majority
please remember I'm generalizing here
are marginalized middle class young
males angry at the world for whatever
reason and who believe and who believe
an RBE is a world where you get any
everything for free and you don't have
to work magic in other words that's just
fucking bullshit in my view and this
kind of membership is neither capable of
achieving anything serious nor do they
have any real moral justice on their
side whereas the black women's rights
movements had tons of moles justice on
this side so basically he was saying you
say no they're bunch of middle class
twit actually from the system saying the
middle of their complaining about it
right okay but then I looked again and I
saw what he just said and so I made it
last bit of the quote because this is a
leader of our movement right he goes nor
do they have any real moral justice on
their side do you get that yeah no we
don't have any moral justice on our side
so that is a believer of laser a leader
of our movement saying that we're just
one set I think you might be slightly
taking out of context that I think he's
talking
about the ideals of the movement he's
talking about the member he's talking
about that membership of it right so the
yeah yeah yeah any more dresses
but regardless who you are whether
you're a hard-working lowly paid uh yeah
manual worker you know or or a spoilt
middle-class Brad you know waste every
the model justice is on your side yeah
yeah the more the morality here is our
world is being screwed up
environmentally ninety percent of
humanity is purposely economically
insecure eighty percent of the global
population lives in poverty you know we
have every justification every moral
right to get off of our backsides and
demand a better world right now I agree
with all of that but I think I think the
point is making the lack of moral
justification comes when your motivate
when your desire for bringing about RBE
is so that you can have everything you
want without having to do any work I
think that's the point that he's making
you like ya know when that is your
motivation I think that's the point that
he's making know what everything he just
said I'm caught I agree with all of that
otherwise we wouldn't be here together
but I think he's absolutely right
exactly I think listen I don't know you
that well but I think you and I are both
in the position where we are seeking to
bring this about not for our own
personal easy life but because we seek
to liberate the spirit of man so that we
can go on to do much better things than
we're currently doing that's where I'm
coming from certainly yeah you know it's
such a strange moving we live it because
we got tbp right the Venus Project and
yeah fed page them you know they got
their agenda and then but somehow I saw
I do doubt whether they'll actually get
their City bill and
if they do get that CD bit what will
happen I'm not sure then we got the
zeitgeist movement who seen whose focus
seemed to be some sort of giving other
non RBE groups a sort of platform to
talk on and I think a lot of light so I
got movement activists actually leave
zeitgeist and go into the the reformist
groups of their giving space - and then
we got like the free world charter and I
think everybody's just hanging out to
see what Colin or Colin does there and
then we got like money free pie and
we're just dead in the war because most
people with our movement you know don't
be like politics if you--if we want to
go forward as a political party in the
in the established way that's how how
they achieved it not my specs we would
actually stand a genuine chance if we
were to organize ourselves we said a
genuine sell one or two MEP selected yes
and and in local elections as well yes
that sounds you know smaller party
started yeah every small party that's
all like got to household name started
like that by getting its first member
related into the smaller assembly and I
know once you've got a couple of
representatives there then you actually
have a platform when it comes to general
election time as well right then you
actually you know yeah you've got a
chance of getting on the telly and
getting getting a little bit of paper
space and so on I think elections and
the upcoming European elections it is
interesting to see how many new small
little niche parties are start with it
was it was a good it is a good time for
that but it was as well before the
credit crunch in 2008 before the credit
crunch in 2008 it was a time for little
pies the little parties and the
independents were just coming on too
strong and then crack the credit crunch
came in we had the Lib Dem and
conservative coalition here that sort of
like everybody got pissed off with that
because the Lib Dems
about student fees except for the next
donation everybody went out to punish
the Lib Dems yeah Tory yeah that's
that's why exactly they did it's it's a
bit strange and going back to that idea
of saying there's no unified sort of
goal within us and no unified movement
it's so true you know I mean my goal
always you know has been to get the
argument get the concept an argument
into public debate and that's where I
want it and I think if all the
organization's
had that as its goal because that's got
to happen yet unless we get this idea
into public debate it's not gonna happen
and it should have happened years ago it
needed to happen years ago you know
we're probably far too late for it now
because the environmental is the
environment is so you know it's been so
trashed you know that's anyway so if we
can just so somehow inspire our
memberships you know to sort of unify
and try to get it out of yo into public
debates we know how to get stuff into
public debate did we see it all the time
Joey we've seen extinction we've been
the thing that they've done which is
basically what you're talking about is
that they have found one issue which
everybody has united behind right now I
mean III don't personally agree with
that as an issue but nevertheless it has
had the power to bring thousands of
people out willing to get arrested
willing to live on the streets for days
on end living you know sleeping in tents
yeah not since occupy have we seen
anything like that if we haven't got the
metal to do that which so far you know
we just don't have any merit or yeah
we'd rather so yeah I mean you probably
before Eddie gets down because yeah
let's face it most of our support base
probably just no yeah were sick you know
we're not really gonna get much further
than that left in it you know so these
these mass movements that come along you
know like the extinction rebellion and
the climate camp and occupy they never
actually really lead to very much all
right mobilize somehow massively this
massive mobilization and where's it go
it doesn't go anywhere okay have you
been following any of the dark side of
it at all on YouTube you've been looking
at it like young round of Gale Bradbrook
yeah yeah yeah yeah I've seen now posted
a few things yeah it makes me very
suspicious and someone that I can't I
can't maybe what his name is he talks
now at speakers corner all the time he's
he's a lefty guy so it's caicos
something like that that's right yeah I
didn't ask you if he'd do an interview
for us actually yeah I think he probably
would
he knows me I've seen maybe you can get
on today yeah I think it was him that
made the point that if this had been a
bunch of demonstrators like anti-war or
anti racism or something like that
there's no way they would have been
allowed to plot up in Marble Arch for
ten days you know I mean and block off
on Saturn yeah yeah you know they were
pushing at an open door I think was the
phrase that I heard used I think that's
a really yeah well when they when they
first saw like arrived on the scene they
saw like this Facebook page and it was
kind of the first thing that sort of
like smacked me in the face was okay you
got this group okay and they're saying
oh we're going to do a campaign of civil
disobedience they were publicly saying
that well what's the first thing that's
gonna happen when a group publicly say
that they're gonna get infiltrated like
hell from various different agencies
trying to sort of direct that movement
into some sort of way you know the
get out Venetian yeah viable effect you
know it's it was a bit crazy
have you made our art of war by Sun
familiar I'm aware of it I've never read
it no yeah people people said to me I'll
read the art of war by Sun Tzu and what
a lot of people said that year for a few
decades and then I eventually read it
now what got me most about the book was
not actually what was what's being said
in the book but that it's 2,000 years
old yeah it was really matters that but
anyway whatever yeah yeah yeah it's been
over 2,000 years ago
and basically it's a tactical summary of
how to manipulate society the art of war
is to get what you want without going to
war without yeah bloodshed and farming
off cannons and wherever so basically
it's a book about strategy about how to
manipulate society how to form social
movements and manipulate social
movements and it's 2,000 years old all
the politicians generals military people
businessman I've been reading this for
2,000 years and building upon that
strategies on those strategies you know
so going back to exile you know I mean
we this is the geography of the
situation we live it we don't know if
they were cut there just to solve direct
or so they see scoop up and direct for
the Revolutionary so creativity and
inspiration of positivity into some cold
East and you know wasted because it so
happens every eighty load and it's worse
than that it's not just directing it
down a cul-de-sac apparently the end
game is to Nick our pension funds office
you had to compare well yeah okay
problem that the only way to solve it is
to spend all the money in the world you
know I mean and then and then where does
that come from is our pension funds yeah
yeah real that the real goal here is to
use the guise of climate change to Nick
our pension fund money in order to prop
up the banks who are in
we gonna collapse you know what I mean
and just kick that can down the road for
another couple of decades well yeah I
mean that yeah we can another fear yeah
but where you can go but you know I mean
the thing is I think the thing is with
people is well the thing is with the
times that we live in
we've got conspiracy theories right yeah
and if you get labeled a conspiracy
theorist you know he's really gonna take
much mainstream we're not going to take
much notice of you right it's all like
yeah it's tinfoil hat stuff but the
thing is like we do conspire and do you
know so there's a great quote from
Theodore Theodore hertzel have you heard
of him use of founder of Zionism okay so
it's a distinguished person Theodor
Herzl and basically he said when he when
they were developing Zionism he said we
will lead every movement against us
yeah do you think you're better you
think about what that means
it's opposition yeah and that's and
that's a hundred-year-old quote yo go
back to the art of war yeah which is
like 2,000 years ago we're dealing you
know women it we're in a situation where
we don't know what the fuck's going on
you know that we've been manipulated
we'd like babies we like intercepted
little people and don't know what the
hell was going on and once we start
starts thinking we do know what's going
on we're fucked
yeah no I don't know where that takes us
yeah it's a shame because I was I was
really excited about it to see to see
you know actual people power being
exerted but yeah the more I've looked at
the dark side of it I came across a
video I don't know a few days ago and
that led me to watch some others and and
yeah I've watched a bit the more I've
become convinced that actually not that
not the grassroots people I mean they're
the way they're acting from the absolute
best of intentions right but the
organizers are the creators of this it's
a false opposition can
yeah yeah going back to the good
intentions yeah so first of all they've
got this little list of demands right
okay and if those demands are met
they're not gonna really radically
achieve anything no bully and they're
saying like a People's Assembly sounds
good but you've got to so realize that
the state of the environment that we're
in now is a result of our values
yeah it's about it's all like putting
profit before environment and that's set
to our values you know society's value
so we're going to create an assembly of
people with those values to sort out the
value do you sweat and I mean there's no
sort of clear thing about how those
people are beaten to be select so I
heard something about a random selection
process a total waste of time and you'd
have to change the whole so yeah you
know put loads of statues through
Parliament to actually get that because
you they basically wanted to overload
Parliament don't they that in a way our
existing system we are supposed to it we
owe that we the electorate are supposed
to have the power to override Parliament
but in a practical day-to-day sense of
course we don't and when it comes to
election time what are our actual
options that we're but you know one of
the actual options we're presented with
yeah yeah
can we going back to our going to hook
up it'll lift code go back to the
intentions of just I've got great crow
and it's my favorite quote actually the
road to hell I mean don't you want to
see about our because we got frenzied
nobody wants to hear about our be
because we got the mostly more nobody
wants to talk about capitalism because
capitalism either producing its own
district distractions for us this whole
climate change narrative could be
exactly that as well a distraction from
actually dealing with the real
ecological disasters going on right now
I mean you know again it comes to words
as now I mean I do believe you know if
we were using the term environmental
degradation yeah thank you mean our
argument because you can't deny nobody
can deny awful devastating offenses that
yo consumerism has absolutely no
environment yeah yeah environmental
degradation yeah you can't do that
global warming well by mental
degradation is a much better term it's
much more encompassing and there's the
air yeah absolutely
that the name of the party money free
party do you not find cuz I've
encountered this a few times in a few
different situations do you not find
people sort of doing things voluntarily
just basically can't rely on them you
know what I mean there's no deadline
there's no quid pro ya home because
we're so conditioned to responding some
money as an incentive to do things you
know what I mean
and it's it's a real problem it's a it's
a real problem that I've seen yeah I
mean I think that's all over the yeah
it's not just down to the money free
pass a big problem you know it's a this
could kind of lead us on to a different
discussion altogether actually yeah ya
know I found that it's just it's just a
pain in the artery I think I think yeah
the collective consciousness is turned
the way forward is yeah
and that requires proper communication
and be faithful in so far as it's
possible to do so transfer of
information and knowledge from one
person to the next right
as soon as knowledge distorted by
individual ideologies along the way well
now the collective doesn't work anymore
you know maybe they're you know sharing
of knowledge and information can only
happen when we're not thinking
it's a non silver ball so communication
is happening honest or deep deeper level
I don't know is a subject did anybody
talk about that do you know yeah
actually a guy called Jordan Hall who I
really really really like he has
unbelievably high-level conversations
and I quite often have to rewind and
listen to bits of it two or three times
to get the whole unbelievably dense
conversations about this so he'd just
very very very quickly on outline his
thing he wrote an essay about this
shortly after Trump came came into power
and he saw that as the end basically the
game a so game a as far as he is
concerned began some tens of thousands
of years ago so for 50,000 years or
whatever human beings were the top
creditor they occupied every niche on
the planet and were the most successful
species on the planet for about 50,000
years until they started to encounter
each other right and at that point game
a began and game a was the solution to
the problem how can larger numbers of
people coexist with each other
collaborate with each other cooperate
with each other without killing each
other all right and so for the last
whatever it is twenty thirty thousand
years we've been playing game a and he
thinks that game a has reached its
zenith now game a did this human society
human ideas technology and so on have
become so complicated now but game a can
no longer cope with it and game a is
coming to an end and we need to start
playing game B and so he then starts to
talk a little bit about what he sees
game B as looking like and they think
Sam a feed what you were just talking
about actually one of the main features
of game B is what is what equals
coherence where people are able to
exactly that come together collectively
and in the interaction between the
people a thing is created which is
bigger than the sum of the parts of
those people you know I mean a an idea
or a structure of thought or whatever is
created which no one of those
individuals could possibly have done on
their own but the collaboration of all
of those things and so coherence is
something like people are sitting around
talking someone says something and most
of all that person says is noise but in
amongst that noise is
no and it is the job of the other people
in that conversation to discern noise
from signal okay what I heard in that
that is useful is this and they react
you late it in a new way repackage it
adding to it something of their own and
so this thing evolves as it moves around
and become Joe Johnston I mean and so
game B is this idea of coherence among
people and how exactly that and really
this needs to occur people being in the
same room so it's about reforming
relationships reforming trust the idea
that information is the most important
thing that we have and that the purity
of information and so you can't he talks
about lots and lots of things but you
can't bring your own agenda to the
information right he talks about the
idea of being full if you're part of a
group of people and you are acting from
a position of fullness like in a jazz
band right you're part of a jazz band
and you're you're insecure and you want
to take over the theme because you want
to show how clever you are right so you
cut someone else off and you introduce
your own theme you're acting from a
place of need you need to actually a
place of fullness because your excellent
place of fullness you really happy to
let the other person do whatever you
need to impose yourself on it right yeah
yeah yeah I'm kind of being that
coherence and again yeah in fact yeah
coherency is also another sort of oil so
dynamic of how minorities influence and
change the values of the majority you
know it's going back to consistency
there's three Caesar come over what the
other ones are I've not been up on it
lately but it's consistently so her
coherency come in with the other one oh
yeah it would be good to sort get that
message across um oh you know to uh I
dunno consistently getting the message
out we can we have this yeah yeah that I
did you know
no no I consistency is a crucial element
that we have that affect the meal people
just seem to be such a minority you know
I mean oh yeah we got groups of
thousands of individuals but within
those thousands of individuals you only
get one person who's gonna be willing to
stand up yeah it's amazing yeah anyway
all right I'll catch me a nice one take
it easy buddy yeah yeah YouTube